CURRICULUM VITAE

OSCAR MURAMBA THOYA

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Oscar Muramba Thoya

Nationality: Kenyan

Languages: English and Kiswahili (written and spoken)
Contacts: E-Mail Address: oscarthoya6@gmail.com

Cell phone: +254 719 774 291

+254 736 640 258

Address: P.O. Box 750, Kilifi

PERSONAL PROFILE

A well organized, self-motivated, and detail-oriented statistician, market researcher and business analytics expert, with a strong academic background and a high affinity to quick decision making. I can skillfully study business objectives and design, conducting and coordinating surveys. I am able to communicate, deliver and interpret data to senior management and colleagues for business recommendations. My data analysis and research formulation skills are second to none.

KEY SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

- o Bachelor of Science in Statistics.
- Excellent project planning, management and organizational skills, including managing multiple projects and tasks concurrently
- Proficient in the use of qualitative analysis and quantitative research, data collection, data cleaning operations and presentation of research findings to high-level policymakers and the general public.
- o Strategic planning, budgeting, documentation, and evaluation.
- o Analyze data using mathematical models and statistical techniques for policy development.
- o Possessing the ability to report complex data or relevant market data in an understandable form.
- o Proficiency in the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation tools and systems.
- o Proficiency in statistical analysis using SPSS, R, Python, SAS, MATLAB and STATA software.
- o Computer programming.
- o Database management.
- o Advanced skills in Ms Excel and Microsoft suite
- o Ability to work independently with minimum supervision and in a team setting.
- o Proficient in Open Data Kit and Survey CTO.
- o Excellent organizational and negotiation skills.
- Excellent interpersonal, analytical thinking and problem-solving skills.
- o Flexible and possessing the ability to manage multiple tasks.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2014 – 2017: South Eastern Kenya University

Bachelor of Science in Statistics-Second Class Honors (Upper Division)

2009 – 2012: Malindi High School, Kenya

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE) - A-

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JOMO KENYATTA UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE AND TECHNOLOGY Support staff-School of mathematical sciences

January 2020-present

empper surj, concert of immuneum serence

- Key Duties and Responsibilities Included:✓ Attending to data request and follow up on the requests.
 - ✓ Undertaking in research design, sampling design on data collection, processing and analysis of data on school objectives.
 - ✓ Statistical data analysis and data validation.
 - ✓ Evaluation and analysis of reports.
 - ✓ Presentation of reports for strategic implementation.

KENYA NATIONAL BUREAU OF STATISTICS Content Supervisor(Census 2019)

August 2019

Key Duties and Responsibilities Included:

- ✓ Assigned Enumerators to a field area for field research.
- ✓ Ensured the field research by enumerators was done on the stipulated time and the set deadlines.
- ✓ Ensured that any equipment was available in the enumeration areas during training and the actual exercise period.
- ✓ Ensured collection of quality and accurate data by the enumerators.
- ✓ Did census enumeration in some resampled households.
- ✓ Collaboration with Village Elders, Assistant Chiefs, or Chief in the identification of all the groups of the population.
- ✓ I made sure that everybody under my assigned field area was enumerated successfully.
- ✓ Ensured proper maintenance of all the equipment used in the field research.
- ✓ Provided feedback and updates to The County Statistics Officer.
- ✓ Ensured data integrity collected from households.
- ✓ Follow up to ensure deadlines were met.

NEEMA YA MUNGU INVESTMENT

Business Development Officer/ Statistician

September 2018 to July 2019

Key Duties and Responsibilities Include:

- ✓ Assessing clients assets and disbursal of loans
- ✓ Marketing of company services
- ✓ Database management of clients records
- ✓ Responsible for loan recovery
- ✓ Business analytics and market research
- ✓ Modeling and providing accurate trend analysis and forecasting of customer base
- ✓ Generating and presenting reports on the performance of disbursals and repayments.

POLE POLE FARM Farm Supervisor

January 2018 to August 2018

Key Duties and Responsibilities Included:

- ✓ Responsible for scheduling, budgeting and record keeping
- ✓ Responsible for the farm inputs and inventory
- ✓ Work hand in hand with the farm consultant and agronomists
- ✓ Setting production targets, analyzing produce trend and forecasting future position of the farm
- ✓ Marketing of farm produce and poultry products

REFERENCES

Md Lena kiptoo: Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Cell: +254 720596702 **Email:** <u>lena@jkuat.ac.ke</u>

• Mr William Waswa: Neema Ya Mungu Investment

Cell: +254 712 465 495

• Mr Sylvester Yawa Rondo: Ronslnd Engineering Company

Cell: +254 718 369 742/+ 254 731 609 912 **Email**: <u>sylvesteryawa@rocketmail.com</u>